# 漆二娃把那个土豆拿过来
Qi Erwa, bring the potatoes here.
# 我们之前说了土豆这个东西怎么去切它
We've talked about how to cut potatoes.
# 土豆丝切得越均匀越好
The more evenly you shred the potatoes, the better.
# 你也知道怎么样去检验它上次我也说了
You know how to test it. I taught you that last time.
# 这次再复习一遍
Let's go over it again now.
# 这个土豆啊
These potatoes.
# 没有买好 是你买的是吧
are not good enough. You bought it, right?
# 是
Yes.
# 焉的
Shriveled.
# 土豆是软的
They are soft.
# 你看削这个土豆
See how I peel this potato?
# 好快啊
That is fast.
# 这个都是原先这个四个手指
I use these four fingers.
# 像这样子被削 指甲都被削了
Peeling in this way, and I used to got my nails peeled off very often.
# 要多受这种小伤你才知道 才会进步
You have to get these little wounds a lot to know how to improve.
# 像这样子切个四方形出来
Cut a square out like this.
# 切个四方形出来 如果土豆大的话它两边还要切
Cut a square out of it. If the potato is big, cut it on both sides.
# 切出来的土豆就是跟火柴一样
The cut potato shreds are just like matches.
# 长短都差不多
They are of the same length.
# 然后大小也均匀就是好看
And looks nice when it's evenly sized.
# 但是浪费这个原材料特别厉害
But this would produce a terrible amount of waste.
# 检验土豆切好没有 上面看着很规整
Check the potato to see if it's cut well. It looks very neat up there.
# 你翻过来一看也要一样的知道吧
You'd have to check the other side, if it's also in good shape.
# 上面跟下面一样的
It's the same as the bottom.
# 这样子一刀一刀的往前面推切
This way, you're pushing and slicing forward.
# 如果你们前面掌握好了
If you've got it right up front.
# 那后面的话就用中段
Then we'll use the middle section.
# 看到没有 这样子切
See? Cut like this.
# 这个考验的是什么呢
What is the challenge?
# 比较考验的是这个土豆有没有按稳
The challenge is to hold the potato steady.
# 我们切土豆丝切的好不好 规不规整
How do we know if we are shredding the potato properly and neatly?
# 土豆丝在这边直上来了啊
If the shredded potato goes straight up on the side (of the knife)
# 直上来的就说明这个土豆丝切方正了 切均匀了
If it's straight up, it means the potato is cut straight and evenly
# 切得不均匀的它这个土豆丝往上面的时候左右到处跑
If it's unevenly sliced, then the shreds run in random directions when they go up on the side (of the knife).
# 看到没有
You see that?
# 然后这个土豆丝切完第一时间放到水里
Put the shredded potato in water straight after cutting it.
# 还算比较标准
It's pretty standard.
# 因为它的土豆丝切了是直接往上面走
Because we see the potato shreds go straight up.
# 还算比较标准
It's pretty standard.
# 你看 我拿一根我切的 你看到没有
Look, I take one of these that I cut, you see?
# 同样的你看你这根就软了
Compared with yours, look at how soft your shreds are.
# 为什么呢
Why is this?
# 因为你下刀的时候没有顺着它的筋切
Because you didn't follow its "tendons" when you cut it.
# 知道吗
Do you understand?
# 你下刀不够顺
You didn't use your knife smoothly enough.
# 全部都是这样
All of them.
# 你再切一颗
You cut another one.
# 方法是用对了 但是土豆切的不均匀
You are using the correct method, but the potato was still not cut evenly.
# 看到没有
You see that?
# 第一是你切片的时候厚度不均匀
Firstly, you didn't slice it in the even thickness.
# 后面是切丝的时候 切丝的那个距离没有控制均匀
And secondly, you didn't shred it evenly.
# 看到没 他的片没打好
See? Your potato slices are not even.
# 还是斜着跑
It is running slantwise?
# 知道吗
Do you understand?
# 他比你好的地方是用力用得比你均匀
What he did better than you is that he used his strength more evenly than you.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 他的厚薄间距控制的比你好
He's got better control of the potato thickness than you.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 我再给你演示一遍
Let me show you again.
# 像这种土豆 就稍微来说比较好切一点
A potato like this, is a little easier to cut.
# 因为它本身就是长的
Because it's long in itself.
# 我们首先这个刀啊 你是刀没有拿稳
First of all, the knife. You didn't hold it steady.
# 你是拿着刀切下去的时候那个力度控制不好
When you're holding the knife to cut, you didn't have good control.
# 下
Force down.
# 你这样拿在手里面转一下
Hold it like this and twirl it around in your hand.
# 土豆丝切出来就是能滚它就很好
It is good if the potato shreds call be rolled.
# 这是我师父以前教我的
My master chef taught me this.
# 不管切多厚多细多粗
No matter how thick or thin you cut the potato,
# 你拿在手里面能滚就说明均匀
as long as you can roll it in your hand, it's even.
# 暂时就是这个样子
That's the way it is for now.
# 这里还有一些土豆
Here are some more potatoes.
# 你们再练吧
You guys practice more.
# 我切这个吧
I'll cut this.
# 你们看着土豆的量来啊
Be careful how many potatoes you cut.
# 要不然你们这个土豆要吃个好几天
Otherwise you'd be eating potatoes for days.
# 我看
Let me see.
# 看 翻过来我看
Let me see, turn it over.
# 来 看哈这就是啥子
Here, look at this. What is this?
# 很典型的
Typical (mistakes of cutting potatoes).
# 噶
Emm.
# 你可以把它切得那么厚 但是你要保证它每一片都那么厚
You can cut it as thick as you want, but you have to make sure that every piece is evenly thick.
# 你可以把它切得那么薄 你也保证每一片都那么薄
You can also slice it as thin as you want, but again you have to make sure they are evenly thin.
# 懂起没有
Do you understand?
# 懂起了
I understand.
# 糟了糟了 你要吃一个月的土豆哦
Oh, no, no, no. You'll be eating potatoes for a month.